<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Vanik Karslian</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Vanik Karslian</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>EN</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.karslian.com/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manage your python-dependancies with Poetry</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2020-08-15-poetry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2020-08-15-poetry/</guid><description>Another daily routine every python developer has is the packages management and control. Python, unlike other programming languages lacks of solid package management tool. pip provides some basic functionality, but still does not have necessary version and dependency management capabilities, required for mission critical python projects.
Version divergence Particularly, when developer adds/updates some packages in h
In this article I am will share some basic tools I recommend to use with every python project.</description></item><item><title>Overview of the data architectures</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-10-07-data-architectures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-10-07-data-architectures/</guid><description>The Data Еnignеering field is a relatively a new area of IT, which is actively developing within the last years.
The field is dynamically changing, and those changes also reflect in the emerging approaches in the architecture. In this article we will briefly cover some of the most popular DWH architectures.
Independent Data Mart Architecture In this architecture, the data marts are highly adjusted to the needs of the specific departments.</description></item><item><title>Resovle python installemnts hassle with Pyenv</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2020-08-07-pyenv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2020-08-07-pyenv/</guid><description>In our daily work we usually deal with multiple python projects that we maintain. It&amp;rsquo;s usually the case that those projects have slightly different python versions. Some of the projects get the frequent updates, some of them might sit somewhere in your hard drive with old, but good python3.7 waiting for the developer to update the version.
The management of the python versions was always a hassle. Especially when it comes to the virtualenvs.</description></item><item><title>Tooling you should use for your python projects</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2020-08-02-python-project-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2020-08-02-python-project-setup/</guid><description>In this article I am will share some basic tools I recommend to use with every python project.
Pyenv The first tool in my daily toolbox is pyenv. Pyenv allows to install and manage multiple python environments at the same time.
Key benefits: you can install any python version available in pypi at your machine time saving: you do not need to care about the installation process, pyevn will do everything for you manages virtualenvironments- it is a single tool to add manage both the python version as well as the virtualenvironments.</description></item><item><title>Travels in time with BigQuery</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-10-07-biq-query-history/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-10-07-biq-query-history/</guid><description>The travels in time are possible in BigQuery. Not many of the BigQuery users are aware of this feature, although it might be incredibly useful in a daily life of any data engineer. There are multiple occasions when you can leverage the benefits of using time travel. Imagine, you run a data pipeline that breaks the result table, or you did a mistake in your sql query that destroyed a table used by other team-mates.</description></item><item><title>Data challenges in Amazon Vendor Central</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-09-28-data-challenges-in-amazon-vendor-central/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-09-28-data-challenges-in-amazon-vendor-central/</guid><description>Intro Hi everyone, in this article I am going to shed some light on the Amazon Vendor Central and explain the challenges that every data engineer faces working with data from Amazon Marketplace.
But first things first. What is Vendor Central and who are the vendors? Vendors are big enterprises that produce and sell their products on Amazon on a large scale, they are key suppliers for Amazon.
Vendor Central is a platform where the vendors manage their sales on Amazon.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Business Intelligence solution for Amazon Vendors</title><link>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-09-27-bi-solution-for-amazon-vendors-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.karslian.com/articles/2022-09-27-bi-solution-for-amazon-vendors-overview/</guid><description>Intro In this post I would like to talk about the Business Intelligence solution for Amazon Vendors we build in FACTOR-A/DEPT. I will shed some light on platforms Amazon provides for the Vendors, and the challenges it brings to the data teams.
Some terms before we start Vendors are big enterprises that produce and sell their products on Amazon on a large scale, they are key suppliers for Amazon.
ASIN - a unique identifier used insided of Amazon for every product, ie product ID inside of Amazon.</description></item></channel></rss>